They are beautiful… but what are they doing in a place like this?
他们很美 但他们在这种地方做什么？
Why are there humans here?
这里为什么会有人类？
Where are the Soshin?
宗慎在哪里？
You act like you're not a human.
你说得好像你不是人类似的
Are you guys monsters too?
你们也是怪物吗？
How cute.
真可爱
Why don't you guys… come and join us?
你们何不过来加入我们？
Join you?
加入你们？
Don't say such a disgusting thing.
别说这种恶心的话
Sorry. It's just that it's been a while since a human has entered here.
对不起 只是因为 好久没有人类进入这里了
Ugh!
呃
I was in the middle of something good.
我正在享受
And you had to bother me.
你却偏偏要打扰我
I'm going to kill you.
我要杀了你
On an island like this, nothing is strange anymore.
在这样的岛上 所有事都见怪不怪了
Whether the Sennin live here or not, that's not the crux of the matter.
无论仙人是否住在这里 这不是问题的关键
What's important is whether those who live on this island are friend or foe.
重要的是住在这个岛上的人是敌是友
That's all that matters.
这才是最重要的
-Wait! -Huh? What is it?
-等等！ -嗯？怎么了？
A child? Is it from the mainland?
一个孩子？是从大陆来的？
Or is it…
还是…
-Gabimaru! -Who's that child?
-画眉丸！ -那个孩子是谁？
What the hell is this bonsai-creature anyway?
这个盆景一般的生物到底是什么？
Is it a type of monster?
是一种怪物吗？
Gabimaru!
画眉丸
That girl knows something about the island.
这个女孩知道关于岛的一些事
She may be our only clue! I'm gonna catch her.
她也许是唯一的线索！ 我现在就去抓她！
But… there's a monster ahead of you.
但是 你面前有个怪物
Huh?
嗯？
I'll leave the rest to you!
剩下的交给你了！
You've gotta be kidding, right?!
你是在跟我开玩笑吧？
Miss Sagiri!
佐切小姐！
I can't take my eyes off of Gabimaru.
我必须盯着画眉丸
Senta, good luck to you!
祝你好运 仙汰
Uh…oh…
呃…
What the heck are you doing?
你到底在干什么？
I don't want to reveal my strategies yet.
我还不想公布我的策略
I want to test it out against someone
我想找人测试一下
and see if my ninjutsu works on these monsters.
看看我的忍术是否对这些怪物有效
You're familiar with this forest.
你很熟悉这片森林
So we will need to talk.
所以我们需要谈谈
Gabimaru!
画眉丸！
What was that? That is not the strength of a child.
那是什么？那可不是孩子该有的力量
Please wait!
请等一下！
We don't mean any harm.
我们不想伤害你
We just want to talk to you for a moment.
我们只想和你聊一会儿
I'm glad… you understand what I'm saying.
我很高兴你听懂了我说的话
This power… it's different from simple arm strength.
这种力量… 它不仅仅是简单的手臂力量
This is unnatural power.
这是非自然的力量
Too many strange things have happened since we arrived here.
自从我们到这里以后 发生了太多奇怪的事情
This girl, the monsters, the statues,
这个女孩、怪物、雕像
and this village. It was supposed to be a simple mission.
还有这个村子 本来只是个简单的任务的
Get the elixir
拿到长生不老药
and return to my wife as an innocent man.
然后无罪释放 回到妻子身边
I don't know if you are human or not, but you look like a girl.
我不知道你是不是人类 但你看起来就像个小女孩
I'd like to go easy on you but…
我想对你宽容点 但是
I'm at my wit's end.
我已经无计可施了
I feel like I'm losing all emotions.
我觉得我好像失去了所有情绪
Gabimaru!
画眉丸！
I’m fed up with all this exhausting work.
我已经受够了这累人的工作
I just want to find the elixir.
我只想找到长生不老药
Don't give me more trouble.
不要给我制造更多麻烦了
-She's crying… -Of course she is.
-她在哭 -当然了
-What should I do? -First, put her down.
-我该怎么做？ -首先 把她放下来
We caught her, so all is good.
我们抓住了她 所以一切都很好
But hey, looking at her, she's…
但是 你看看她 她…
Just a normal child, isn't she?
只是个普通的孩子 不是吗？
Hey? What the heck is going on?
喂 到底发生什么事了？
What is this family-like atmosphere?
这种温馨的家庭气氛是怎么回事？
I worked my ass off you know.
我可是拼死拼活地工作
What shall we do now?
我们现在该怎么做？
I want to ask her about the elixir.
我想问她关于长生不老药的事
We'll have to wait until she stops crying.
我们得等到她哭完以后
Who's good at comforting kids?
谁擅长哄孩子？
I beg you…
我求你们…
Did it just talk?
它说话了吗？
I beg you… please give me back that child.
求你们把那个孩子还给我
In exchange, I'll lead you to the village.
作为交换 我会带你们去村子里
I'll tell you about the elixir.
我会告诉你们长生不老药的事
No, thank you.
谢谢 不用了
You may be able to talk, but you might be trying to trick us.
你也许会说话 但你更有可能想要骗我们
It's safer if we ask the girl.
问那个女孩更安全
She has a point.
她说得有道理
We also have food in the village.
村子里还有食物
No, thank you.
不了 谢谢
We have baths as well.
还可以洗澡
Bath time! Fun time!
洗澡咯！好开心！
You think we can trust it?
你觉得我们能信任它？
We don't even know what it is.
我们连它是什么都不知道
At this point, it doesn't matter what he is.
现在它是什么并不重要
As long as we can find out more about the elixir.
只要我们能找到 长生不老药的更多信息
If he makes a suspicious move, we'll take him down.
如果他做出可疑举动 我们就干掉他
We're here.
我们到了
It's more like a ghost town than a village.
比起村庄 它更像是一座鬼城
It's so foggy.
雾好大
I don't see anybody else here.
我看不到任何其他人
It wasn't like this 1,000 years ago.
一千年前不是这样的
1,000 years ago?
一千年前？
I'll show you to my house.
我带你们去我家
What amazing ornaments.
多么神奇的装饰品
They all look old. Do you really live here?
它们看起来都好旧 你真的住在这里吗？
I don't lie.
我不撒谎
Let's get down to business…
我们说正事吧
Huh? You can do that later!
嗯？这个可以一会儿再说！
-Bath time first! -We don't have time for that.
-先洗澡吧！ -我们可没时间做那个
This is what I'm talking about.
就是这样
This is great!
太舒服了！
Do something about that woman.
你得管管那个女人
She's impossible to handle.
她完全不好对付啊
That girl is an obedient one.
那个女孩很听话
Take it easy. It's better to relax when you can.
放轻松 能放松的时候还是尽量放松吧
-You want to bathe togethe--? -No.
-你想一起洗… -不要
He's so stubborn. Even you're gonna take a bath, right, Sagirin?
他太固执了 即使是你 也会来洗澡吧 佐切？
Sagirin? I'm just here to watch over you.
佐切？我只是在这里看着你
It's uncomfortable if it's Senta, right?
如果是仙汰的话 会很不舒服吧？
We're just temporarily changing roles.
我们只是暂时改变角色
I haven't forgotten my original role…
我没有忘记我原来的角色
at all.
完全没有
This bath is so relaxing, I can't help myself.
这个浴缸真让人放松 简直无法自拔
We came here so brazenly and now we're making ourselves at home like this.
我们如此厚颜无耻地来到这里 我们又像在自己家一样
Are those towels? Thank you very much.
那些是毛巾吗？太感谢了
I think she likes you.
我想她喜欢你
I wonder if she can't speak?
我在想她是不是不会说话？
There's a well and a vessel.
这里有一口井和一艘船
Wait until we know it's true intentions.
先等到我们弄清它的真实意图
You're right…
你是对的
We have food as well.
我们还有食物
Anyway, let's ask him about the island right away
不管了 我们直接问他关于岛的事吧
and then…
然后…
If you're that hungry, go ahead. I warned you.
如果你这么饿的话 就吃吧 但我警告过你了
There's no poison inside. The girl will eat this too.
里面没有毒 那女孩也吃这个
What's your relationship with her?
你跟她是什么关系？
I have no intention of telling you.
我并不打算告诉你
I see.
这样啊
To be honest, I'm only interested in the elixir.
说实话 我只对长生不老药感兴趣
It's about time you tell us about
你是时候告诉我们
this island and the whereabouts of the elixir.
关于这座岛的事 和长生不老药的下落了
Wow, it's food!
哇 是好吃的
Why are you already eating?!
你怎么已经开始吃了？
I'm sorry…
对不起
I'm gonna have some too. Let me have some now.
我也要吃一点 我现在就吃
This is completely…
这完全…
Throwing us off, isn't it?
让我们失望了 不是吗？
You're not going to eat?
你不吃吗？
I didn't come here to eat.
我不是来这里吃饭的
I don't know what humans call this place,
我不知道人类是怎么叫这个地方的
but we call it "Kotaku."
但我们把它叫做“家宅”
It is where the gods live, also known as Shinsenkyo.
是众神居住的地方 又名神仙境
It's quite different from what I imagined of gods and Shinsenkyo.
这跟我想象中的 众神和神仙境差太远了
I thought gods were more spiritual creatures.
我认为神是更灵性的生物
I've never left this island,
我从未离开过这座岛
so I don't know about those kind of things.
所以我不懂那种东西
Is there really an elixir of immortality?
真的有长生不老药吗？
Of course there is. The ancient legend says so.
当然有 古老的传说是这样说的
According to the legend, the elixir is referred to as "tan."
根据传说 长生不老药被称为“棕褐色”
it is the source of everlasting life.
它是永生的源泉
Tan?
棕褐色？
Not the orange?
不是橘色？
Where is it?
它在哪里？
The island is made up of three regions.
该岛由三个区域组成
The region which holds the forest and the beach is Eishu.
拥有森林和海滩的地区是英树
This region here is called Hojo.
这个区域被称为北条
Tan is in the Horai region.
棕褐色在蓬莱区域
It is located at the center of the island, beyond the fog.
它位于岛的中心 迷雾之上
This is very promising information!
真是非常有用的信息
Searching that forest was pointless!
搜索那片森林毫无意义
And it has nothing to do with the orange!
而且它跟橘色毫无关系
The elixir exists.
长生不老药确实存在
I can return to my wife.
我能回到我妻子身边
Have you seen it with your own eyes?
你亲眼见过它吗？
No… Do you have proof that what you're saying is true?
不 你有证据证明你所说属实吗？
You will meet them eventually.
你最终会遇到他们的
Once you do, you won't doubt a thing.
遇到之后 你就不会再有任何怀疑了
Once you meet Lord Tensen.
一旦你遇到天仙大人
They are immortal and youthful.
他们是不朽的 青春的
They are forever beautiful, perfect creatures.
他们是永远美丽的完美生物
You likely have fought numerous Soshin up until now.
到现在为止 你可能打过无数次宗慎
But the Tensen are on a different level.
但天仙是另一个级别的
No one is a match for them.
没有人是他们的对手
You're probably wondering why I'm welcoming you into my home,
你们也许在想 我为什么带你们回我的家
and telling you everything I know.
还把一切都告诉你们
It's an act of pity.
我是出于同情
Because that will be the last thing you wish for.
因为那将是你最不希望的事情
Every human who lands on this island will eventually die.
每个登陆这座岛屿的人最终都会死去
Lord Tensen won't let anyone go.
天仙大人不会让任何人离开
What do you mean by "every human will die?"
“每个人类都会死”是什么意思？
So you're trying to trick us after all.
所以你的确是在欺骗我们
I am neither friend nor foe.
我既不是朋友 也不是敌人
I'm just telling the truth.
我只是说出事实
Every human who enters the island will be killed by Lord Tensen.
每一个进入岛上的人 都会被天仙大人杀死
Who the hell is this Lord Tensen?
这个天仙大人到底是谁？
He's the most powerful being on this island.
他是这个岛上是最强大的存在
They control the Soshin and punish any sinners.
他们控制着宗慎并惩罚罪人
Especially those who intrude on the island.
特别是入侵岛屿的人
But no need to worry.
但是不用担心
Humans that are punished not only die,
被惩罚的人类不仅仅会死亡
they transform into beautiful flowers.
他们还会变成美丽的花朵
They are released from sin and uncleanness and they attain eternal bliss.
他们被从罪恶和污秽中释放 获得永恒的幸福
The life that becomes a flower becomes the source of tan.
成为花朵的生命 成为棕褐色的来源
That's just what the legend says, right?
但这只是传说 对吧？
There's no way I can believe that.
我绝对不相信
The elixir of immortality exists for sure.
长生不老药肯定是存在
I benefit from it as well.
我也从中受益
He grew back!
他长回来了
You mentioned earlier that you've existed for 1,000 years but…
你之前提到 你已经存在了一千年 但是…
Is she the same as you too?
她跟你也是一样的吗？
Don't point your sword at people!
别用剑指着别人
Huh?
嗯？
Dang, she's so scary.
该死的 她太可怕了
Oh… sorry about that.
对不起
Whether you believe or not, this place is Shinsenkyo.
不管你相不相信 这里就是神仙境
The consequences intruders pay are god's will.
入侵者付出的代价是神的旨意
Escaping the island is no easy task.
逃离岛屿绝非易事
Are you going to follow me to the bath?
你要跟着我去洗澡吗？
Senta didn't take over for me.
仙汰没有来接替我
I'm only going to wash my wounds so I don't mind.
我只是去洗伤口 所以我不介意
At least now you're not slacking on the job.
至少现在你没有懈怠工作
I wasn't slacking.
我之前也没有懈怠
Yes, you were.
你有
You were dozing off after you got out of the bath.
你在洗完澡后打瞌睡了
-No, I wasn't. -Yes, you were.
-我没有 -你有
This guy's so persistent.
这家伙太执着了
The island is made up of three regions.
这座岛由三个区域组成
The elixir is in the center region, the Horai.
长生不老药在中心区域 蓬莱
The elixir is protected by Lord Tensen.
它受天仙大人保护
We have new intel but they are only pieces of information.
我们有新的情报 但它们只是一些信息
Do you think we can trust what he's saying?
你觉得我们能相信他说的话吗？
My name is Hoko. The girl is Mei.
我的名字是浩哥 这个女孩叫梅
We were born and raised in this village
我们在这个村子里出生、长大
for several hundred years.
到现在已经几百年了
We just want to continue to live here in peace. So don't get in our way.
我们只想继续安静地生活在这里 所以请不要妨碍我们
I don't think he's lying but…
我觉得他没有撒谎 但是
I can't believe every word he's saying.
我无法相信他说的每一句话
Especially…
特别是…
About Lord Tensen?
关于天仙大人的？
Lord Tensen is a Shenxian philosophy.
天仙大人是个神仙哲学
They refer to Sennin of the highest ranking.
他们指的是最高等级的仙人
The terms "Soshin" and "Horai"
“宗慎”和 “蓬莱”这两个词
are likely words of Taoist origin.
很有可能出自道教
We can solve that riddle later.
我们可以稍后解开这个谜语
What matters is if they’ll be a problem when obtaining the elixir.
重要的是当我们取长生不老药时 他们会不会成为问题
I want to avoid unnecessary things…
我想尽可能避免…
as much as possible.
不必要的事情
Oh… um…
呃…
Hey! What do you think you're doing?!
等等 你知道你在干什么吗？
Can't you see? I'm going to wash my wounds.
你看不到吗？我要洗我的伤口
Can't you see that she's taking a bath.
你没看到她正在洗澡吗？
What's the big deal?
有什么问题吗？
In the village, men and women, young and old, bathed in the same bath.
在村子里 男人和女人 老人和小孩 都一起洗澡
Only the village chief had his own bath.
只有村长有自己的浴室
Is this the time to worry about bath etiquette?
现在是担心沐浴礼仪的时候吗？
Looking closely, her hair and skin are a wreck.
仔细观察 她的头发和皮肤糟透了
Bathing supplies are available, but not used.
有洗浴用品 但没用过
Does she not have a parental figure who can teach her such things?
她身边没有父母之类的人 教她这些事吗？
I utilized the available bathing supplies
我利用了可用的沐浴用品
and recreated an Edo style bathhouse.
重建了一个江户风格的浴室
So that both parties can enjoy the bathing experience,
让双方都能享受沐浴体验
I will be in charge here.
这里我来负责
What is the meaning of this?
做这些有什么意义？
It's the least I can do to repay her.
为了报答她 这是我力所能及的事
I owe her for a night's lodging and a meal.
我欠她一晚住宿和一顿饭
Also, you are too tense.
还有 你太紧绷了
You should rest when you can.
你应该尽可能休息
If you want to wash your body, please use that.
如果你想洗身体 就请用它
My parents made me help out with the bathing, so I'm quite good at it.
我的父母让我帮忙洗澡 所以我很擅长
This a mixture of ashes and oil cake of the camellia flower.
这是山茶花的灰烬和油饼的混合物
It's not much but I brought this from the mainland.
东西不多 但是我从大陆带来的
I will wash your hair with this.
我用它给你洗头发
Look how clean you are.
看看你现在多干净
I cannot remove your scars but…
我没办法除掉疤痕 但是
don't you feel much better now?
你一定感觉好多了吧？
What are you guys doing?
你们在干什么？
For God's sake, we have a million things to think about…
看在神的份上 我们有一百万件事要考虑
And that girl…
还有那个女孩…
You're too tense, dear.
你太紧绷了 亲爱的
It's in the toughest situations
在最艰难的情况下
that we need to take a good rest like this.
我们才需要像这样放松
Is that so?
是这样吗？
Yes, it is.
没错
We're husband and wife.
我们是夫妻
There's no need to blush each time I wash your back.
没必要每次给你洗背时都脸红
-Is that so? -Yes, it is.
-是吗？ -没错
I'm not blushing.
我没有脸红
I just don't like baths that much.
我只是不太喜欢洗澡
I have a feeling that it'll wash away all that I need to fight.
我有一种感觉 它会把我需要战斗的一切都洗掉
Wow!
哇！
Are you saying I'm washing away your luck?
你是说我把你的运气都洗掉了吗？
That's not what I meant!
我不是那个意思
You are too tense, dear.
你太紧绷了 亲爱的
You should rest when you can,
你应该尽可能地休息
or else you'll collapse before a real battle.
不然在真正的战斗来临之前 你就倒下了
A real battle?
真正的战斗？
Is there a big battle coming up?
会有大战来临吗？
No, it's a battle called life.
不 那是叫做生活的战斗
Be calm and just,
保持冷静和公正
while standing by your beliefs.
同时坚持自己的信念
At times you may push through, and at times you may hide.
有时你可能会挺过去 有时你可能会躲起来
But you will never let go.
但你永远不会放手
It's nothing compared to Kawanakajima.
与川中岛相比 这算不了什么
Life is an extremely long battle.
人生是一场极其漫长的战斗
You are the military general and I'm the military commander.
你是将军 我是指挥官
Taking a good rest is strategic advice.
好好休息是战略建议
I got it.
我懂了
Lastly, let's soak in the bath.
最后 我们泡个澡吧
-No way! -Huh?
-不要！ -嗯？
I don't like soaking in the bath.
我不喜欢泡澡
I'm clean already so there's no need to.
我已经干净了 所以没有必要
You're like a cat.
你真像一只猫
Starting from tomorrow, it's just you and me.
明天开始 只有你和我了
We can no longer use my father's bath.
我们不能再用父亲的浴缸了
Fine!
好吧！
As general, can I share with you some strategic advice too?
作为将军 我能与你共享战略建议吗？
Yes, please do.
是的 请
Don't hide your scar with your hair.
不要用头发遮挡你的疤痕
You may have your reasons but it doesn't bother me.
你也许有你的原因 但我不介意
There's no need for you to hide it.
你没必要把它藏起来
No, this is simply a hairstyle I like.
不 这只是因为我喜欢这个发型
What? Really?
什么？真的吗？
But if you say so…
但如果你这么说
I won't hide it anymore. Thank you.
我不会再藏起来了 谢谢你
Young lady…
小女孩
if you're ashamed of your scars, don't be.
如果你为你的疤痕感到不好意思 请不要这样
That's not easy for a woman.
对女人来说这可不容易
That's not true.
那不是真的
I know a woman who has a big scar.
我认识一个女人 她有一个大疤痕
But she is the most beautiful person I know.
但她是我认识的最美丽的人
Outer appearance is no big deal at all.
外表根本没什么大不了的
Why are you giving me that look?
你为什么这么看我？
What you said was so decent that I was taken aback.
你说得太正经了 令我吃了一惊
He may not be a bad guy by nature.
也许他不是个天生坏人
A part of me feels that way.
一部分的我是这么想的
Though little by little, maybe he's starting to change.
虽然只是一点一点 但也许他开始改变了
I feel refreshed.
我感到神清气爽
I can calmly recall now
我现在可以冷静地想起
what I need to prioritize.
我需要优先考虑的事情了
There's no time to waste.
没有时间可以浪费
I can recall it all now.
我现在想起来了
Subtitle translation by: Mel Nishi
字幕翻译：朱未耒